<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Computational Creativity and Archaeological Data</title>
    <link>https://shawngraham.github.io/CCAD/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Computational Creativity and Archaeological Data</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shawngraham.github.io/CCAD/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hallucinatory Archaeological Landscapes</title>
      <link>https://shawngraham.github.io/CCAD/gan-images/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shawngraham.github.io/CCAD/gan-images/</guid>
      <description>Generative adversarial networks can &amp;lsquo;paint&amp;rsquo; images or retrieve &amp;lsquo;photographs&amp;rsquo; of things that never existed. We are training a GAN on a series of site photographs as part of a 3d photogrammetry workflow, to computationally hallucinate the site. Below are some examples of other GAN projects
 GAN Gogh A project by Kenny Jones and Derrick Bonafilia, training a GAN on European Masters. Their code repo is on Github. Write-up on Towards Data Science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What _is_ computational creativity, anyway?</title>
      <link>https://shawngraham.github.io/CCAD/what-is-computational-creativity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shawngraham.github.io/CCAD/what-is-computational-creativity/</guid>
      <description>Computational creativity is what happens when we try to use the machine as a creative partner, a shattered prism, a performance enhancing drug. It&amp;rsquo;s a wonderful partnership between the machine, art, and humanistic understanding of the past. One of the best examples I can think of right now is Ferraby and St. John&amp;rsquo;s Soundmarks &amp;lsquo;using sound and visual art to explore and animate the sub-surface landscape of Aldborough Roman Town in North Yorkshire, UK&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting underway</title>
      <link>https://shawngraham.github.io/CCAD/getting-underway/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shawngraham.github.io/CCAD/getting-underway/</guid>
      <description>I have spent a lot of time this afternoon getting this website up and running. But success!
I&amp;rsquo;ve also got some generative and siamese network experiments underway
some blurry computer hallucinations of a cleaned excavation trench</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://shawngraham.github.io/CCAD/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shawngraham.github.io/CCAD/about/</guid>
      <description>inspirational quote on computational creativity
 and now a depressing quote about archaeological data
  This project is my contribution to the larger CRANE - Computational Research in the Ancient Near East. With my research students, we are exploring ways we can creatively reuse legacy archaeological data (whether from the Ancient Near East or elsewhere) to generate new insights, new inspirations, new enchantments.
Sara Perry writes,
 I believe archaeology can change the world for the better through its inherent and highly distinctive capacity to generate wonder and enchantment among human beings.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>