<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>recap on Computational Creativity and Archaeological Data</title>
    <link>https://shawngraham.github.io/CCAD/tags/recap/</link>
    <description>Recent content in recap on Computational Creativity and Archaeological Data</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shawngraham.github.io/CCAD/tags/recap/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What Happened to 2021-2022?</title>
      <link>https://shawngraham.github.io/CCAD/year-in-review-2021-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shawngraham.github.io/CCAD/year-in-review-2021-2022/</guid>
      <description>General Thrust of Our Group This Year Last year, we moved to more of a skunkworks approach, where I provided some overall direction, but allowed the team to follow their nose where&amp;rsquo;er it leads. In general terms, we&amp;rsquo;re taking an approach to using computer vision to archaeological imagery, for both research, outreach, and as a lens through which we deform the past, to bring new elements into view
Graduates  Completed MA for Jeff Blackadar, History with Data Science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Happened to 2020 - 2021?</title>
      <link>https://shawngraham.github.io/CCAD/year-in-review-2020-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shawngraham.github.io/CCAD/year-in-review-2020-2021/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m not entirely sure. We were all busy, but it was the kind of busy that doesn&amp;rsquo;t really translate into immediate products. The problem with working with legacy datasets is finding legacy datasets you can work with. But really&amp;hellip; the world&amp;rsquo;s been on fire. Things slipped down the cracks.
Some of the team graduated. Emma Gillies has moved on, after using what she learned here to visually analyze the evolution of Canadian craft beer labels (!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
