<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Project Updates on Computational Creativity and Archaeological Data</title>
    <link>https://shawngraham.github.io/CCAD/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Project Updates on Computational Creativity and Archaeological Data</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shawngraham.github.io/CCAD/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What Happened to 2021-2022?</title>
      <link>https://shawngraham.github.io/CCAD/year-in-review-2021-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shawngraham.github.io/CCAD/year-in-review-2021-2022/</guid>
      <description>General Thrust of Our Group This Year Last year, we moved to more of a skunkworks approach, where I provided some overall direction, but allowed the team to follow their nose where&amp;rsquo;er it leads. In general terms, we&amp;rsquo;re taking an approach to using computer vision to archaeological imagery, for both research, outreach, and as a lens through which we deform the past, to bring new elements into view
Graduates  Completed MA for Jeff Blackadar, History with Data Science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Happened to 2020 - 2021?</title>
      <link>https://shawngraham.github.io/CCAD/year-in-review-2020-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shawngraham.github.io/CCAD/year-in-review-2020-2021/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m not entirely sure. We were all busy, but it was the kind of busy that doesn&amp;rsquo;t really translate into immediate products. The problem with working with legacy datasets is finding legacy datasets you can work with. But really&amp;hellip; the world&amp;rsquo;s been on fire. Things slipped down the cracks.
Some of the team graduated. Emma Gillies has moved on, after using what she learned here to visually analyze the evolution of Canadian craft beer labels (!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fall 2019 Recap</title>
      <link>https://shawngraham.github.io/CCAD/fall-term-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shawngraham.github.io/CCAD/fall-term-recap/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve done not a particularly good job of keeping this website up to date. But we have been busy.
In the fall, we arranged for some more data science training for Jeff, and he&amp;rsquo;s been working hard on learning Keras and other packages and approaches for the various tasks we have in mind for this project. I&amp;rsquo;ve been reposting some of his open research notes here, but since I&amp;rsquo;ve fallen behind, I&amp;rsquo;ll just link over to his notes here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Chatbots?</title>
      <link>https://shawngraham.github.io/CCAD/chatbots/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shawngraham.github.io/CCAD/chatbots/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve made a number of twitterbots, and one or two facebook messenger bots. In my lesson on making twitterbots for the Programming Historian I wrote:
 I believe also that there is space in digital history and the digital humanities more generally for creative, expressive, artistic work. I belive that there is space for programming historians to use the affordances of digital media to create things that could not otherwise exist to move us, to inspire us, to challenge us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a set of images for image recognition</title>
      <link>https://shawngraham.github.io/CCAD/creating-a-set-of-images-for-image-recognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shawngraham.github.io/CCAD/creating-a-set-of-images-for-image-recognition/</guid>
      <description>crossposted from Jeff&amp;rsquo;s blog. Jeff is an MA History and Data Science student @CarletonU.
I would like to train an image recognition model with my own images to see how well it works. Here I want to use the obverse of coins to make a model to recognize the portraits of Elizabeth II (younger), Elizabeth II (more mature), George VI and Abraham Lincoln.
Initially I used 5 cent coins but I found they reflected too much light to take a good photograph so I switched to 1 cent coins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computational Creativity and Archaeological Data Project - Getting Started</title>
      <link>https://shawngraham.github.io/CCAD/jeff-getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shawngraham.github.io/CCAD/jeff-getting-started/</guid>
      <description>crossposted from Jeff&amp;rsquo;s blog. Jeff is an MA History and Data Science student @CarletonU.
I am doing research for the Computational Creativity and Archaeological Data project. My current challenge has been to use techniques from Computer Vision to analyse images relevant to Computational Research on the Ancient Near East (CRANE) with the goal to provide additional understanding of these images. Computer Vision and machine learning could identify and classify elements in images or provide a possible reconstruction of a partial artifact using an image of it combined with a model of images of related artifacts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Jeff Blackadar</title>
      <link>https://shawngraham.github.io/CCAD/introducing-jeff-blackadar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shawngraham.github.io/CCAD/introducing-jeff-blackadar/</guid>
      <description>Jeff Blackadar is a part-time MA student in the Department of History, pursuing an MA in History with Data Science. As an undergrad, he published a lesson on MySQL with R in The Programming Historian. His work on the CCAD project will explore techniques of in-painting and image completion on archaeological photography, and the ways these images can be used for photogrammetry and the exploration of &amp;lsquo;fuzziness&amp;rsquo; in computational imagination / archaeological reconstruction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hallucinatory Archaeological Landscapes</title>
      <link>https://shawngraham.github.io/CCAD/gan-images/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shawngraham.github.io/CCAD/gan-images/</guid>
      <description>Generative adversarial networks can &amp;lsquo;paint&amp;rsquo; images or retrieve &amp;lsquo;photographs&amp;rsquo; of things that never existed. We are training a GAN on a series of site photographs as part of a 3d photogrammetry workflow, to computationally hallucinate the site.
Below are some examples of other GAN projects
 GAN Gogh A project by Kenny Jones and Derrick Bonafilia, training a GAN on European Masters. Their code repo is on Github. Write-up on Towards Data Science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What _is_ computational creativity, anyway?</title>
      <link>https://shawngraham.github.io/CCAD/what-is-computational-creativity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shawngraham.github.io/CCAD/what-is-computational-creativity/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s late at night, and I&amp;rsquo;m trying to pound out some words so that I have it on the screen what, roughly, I think is the/an answer to this question. I will come back to this over and over again during this project, I&amp;rsquo;m sure. Expect non-sequiturs.
In their introduction to the issue of Internet Archaeology devoted to digital creativity, Gareth Beale and Paul Reilly point out how archaeologists tend to downplay the &amp;lsquo;theoretical implications [of digital tools] and to characterise methodological transformation in terms of technological innovation&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting underway</title>
      <link>https://shawngraham.github.io/CCAD/getting-underway/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shawngraham.github.io/CCAD/getting-underway/</guid>
      <description>I have spent a lot of time this afternoon getting this website up and running. But success!
I&amp;rsquo;ve also got some generative and siamese network experiments underway
some blurry computer hallucinations of a cleaned excavation trench</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
