<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>image_recognition on Computational Creativity and Archaeological Data</title>
    <link>https://shawngraham.github.io/CCAD/tags/image_recognition/</link>
    <description>Recent content in image_recognition on Computational Creativity and Archaeological Data</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shawngraham.github.io/CCAD/tags/image_recognition/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What Happened to 2021-2022?</title>
      <link>https://shawngraham.github.io/CCAD/year-in-review-2021-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shawngraham.github.io/CCAD/year-in-review-2021-2022/</guid>
      <description>General Thrust of Our Group This Year Last year, we moved to more of a skunkworks approach, where I provided some overall direction, but allowed the team to follow their nose where&amp;rsquo;er it leads. In general terms, we&amp;rsquo;re taking an approach to using computer vision to archaeological imagery, for both research, outreach, and as a lens through which we deform the past, to bring new elements into view
Graduates  Completed MA for Jeff Blackadar, History with Data Science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Happened to 2020 - 2021?</title>
      <link>https://shawngraham.github.io/CCAD/year-in-review-2020-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shawngraham.github.io/CCAD/year-in-review-2020-2021/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m not entirely sure. We were all busy, but it was the kind of busy that doesn&amp;rsquo;t really translate into immediate products. The problem with working with legacy datasets is finding legacy datasets you can work with. But really&amp;hellip; the world&amp;rsquo;s been on fire. Things slipped down the cracks.
Some of the team graduated. Emma Gillies has moved on, after using what she learned here to visually analyze the evolution of Canadian craft beer labels (!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fall 2019 Recap</title>
      <link>https://shawngraham.github.io/CCAD/fall-term-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shawngraham.github.io/CCAD/fall-term-recap/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve done not a particularly good job of keeping this website up to date. But we have been busy.
In the fall, we arranged for some more data science training for Jeff, and he&amp;rsquo;s been working hard on learning Keras and other packages and approaches for the various tasks we have in mind for this project. I&amp;rsquo;ve been reposting some of his open research notes here, but since I&amp;rsquo;ve fallen behind, I&amp;rsquo;ll just link over to his notes here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a set of images for image recognition</title>
      <link>https://shawngraham.github.io/CCAD/creating-a-set-of-images-for-image-recognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shawngraham.github.io/CCAD/creating-a-set-of-images-for-image-recognition/</guid>
      <description>crossposted from Jeff&amp;rsquo;s blog. Jeff is an MA History and Data Science student @CarletonU.
I would like to train an image recognition model with my own images to see how well it works. Here I want to use the obverse of coins to make a model to recognize the portraits of Elizabeth II (younger), Elizabeth II (more mature), George VI and Abraham Lincoln.
Initially I used 5 cent coins but I found they reflected too much light to take a good photograph so I switched to 1 cent coins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Learning with Python, Appendix A</title>
      <link>https://shawngraham.github.io/CCAD/notebooks/jeff-first-book-mnist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shawngraham.github.io/CCAD/notebooks/jeff-first-book-mnist/</guid>
      <description>Jeff&amp;rsquo;s initial experiment with a Google Colab notebook, on the mnist dataset.
&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://colab.research.google.com/github/jeffblackadar/image_work/blob/master/deep_learning_with_python_appendix_a.ipynb&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_parent&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;https://colab.research.google.com/assets/colab-badge.svg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;Open In Colab&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two notebooks for taking photos</title>
      <link>https://shawngraham.github.io/CCAD/notebooks/jeff-photos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shawngraham.github.io/CCAD/notebooks/jeff-photos/</guid>
      <description>A notebook within which you may control your device&amp;rsquo;s camera to take photos. 
A notebook for taking photos and removing backgrounds.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
